[
  {
    "question": "Which of the following program element is used to hold value in memory?",
    "options": { "A": "Variable", "B": "Comments", "C": "Operators", "D": "All of above" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a Standard Numeric Data type in Python?",
    "options": { "A": "Integer", "B": "Floating", "C": "Boolean", "D": "Complex" },
    "correct": "C"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following represents the Mapping Data type in Python?",
    "options": { "A": "List", "B": "Dictionary", "C": "Tuple", "D": "Set" },
    "correct": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ______ keyword is used to define a null value, or no value in Python?",
    "options": { "A": "Nothing", "B": "Null", "C": "Zero", "D": "None" },
    "correct": "D"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ______ keyword is used to represent the True/False value in Python.",
    "options": { "A": "bool", "B": "boolean", "C": "Boolean", "D": "None" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "For creating a list in Python, we write data items in __________.",
    "options": { "A": "Parenthesis", "B": "Square brackets", "C": "Curley Brackets", "D": "Angular Brackets" },
    "correct": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________ in Python are used to represent Unicode character values.",
    "options": { "A": "String", "B": "Tuple", "C": "List", "D": "Set" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________ types are those types whose contents are allowed to be changed after the creation.",
    "options": { "A": "Mutable", "B": "Immutable", "C": "None", "D": "Mapping" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an Arithmetic Operator in Python?",
    "options": { "A": "/", "B": "//", "C": "**", "D": "++" },
    "correct": "D"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following function(s) is used for type conversion?",
    "options": { "A": "int()", "B": "float()", "C": "str()", "D": "All of above" },
    "correct": "D"
  }
]
